# Jeris Alan Jawahar

Address: 2510-204, Avent Ferry Road, Raleigh, NC 27606 E-Mail: jjawaha@ncsu.edu | alan.jeris@gmail.com

Phone: +1 (919) 917 0067 | GitHub: jerisalan | LinkedIn: jerisalan

## **Professional Summary**

I am a passionate and budding programmer by profession with 2+ years experience in data mining and visualization and web application development using Java and JavaScript coupled with quick learning and skilled problem solving ability.

## **Work Experience**

Cerner CorporationBangalore, IndiaSoftware EngineerJuly 2014-July 2016

- Prototyped and developed a robust, scalable framework (JavaScript frontend & backend) for MPages, a web based EHR, to support data localization specific to any new locale leading to exponential growth in client usage crossing more than 3 billion page loads every month.
- Developed an Artificial Intelligence based recommender system (JavaScript frontend + Java backend) to support ICD-10 diagnosis concepts for determining right CPT billing fee by physicians.
- Developed a full-blown TimeZone supported JavaScript Date-Time library to parse, validate, manipulate and display dates.

#### Software Engineer Intern

Dec 2013-June 2014

 Developed an automated Test Driven Development Framework using QUnit and jQuery libraries for MPages Platform leading to incorporation of unit tests and facilitated writing quality code.

#### **Blisslogix Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd**

Chennai, India

Android Developer Intern

May 2012–June 2012

 Developed an Android app <u>Sify Gold and Silver Live</u>, which provides live gold prices, commodity market charts and tools to calculate gold and silver rates across the various Indian metros.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Java (solid, day to day use); HTML/CSS, Oracle SQL, C++,
  C (Intermediate); R, Python, Node.js, MySQL (novice)
- Operating Systems: Experience with a wide range of Windows and UNIX environments.
- Miscellaneous: Android SDK, Eclipse IDE, Agile Methodology, React.js, Machine Learning

#### **Education**

### **North Carolina State University**

Expected May 2018

GPA: 9.05/10

Master of Science in Computer Science

#### **Vellore Institute of Technology**

June 2010-May 2014

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

o Awarded merit-based undergraduate scholarship for excellence in academics

o Member of National Social Service and volunteered in teaching under-privileged rural children.

#### **Technical Projects**

- News Classification (Aug 2016 Nov 2016) Led a team of 4 to develop an application (using Python) to automatically classify newsgroup content into respective categories using Multinomial NB & Support Vector Machines and obtained accuracy ranging between 70-85%.
- Diabetes Prediction (July 2013 Oct 2013) Developed a classification model using supervised machine learning methods for identifying main causes of diabetes and predicting whether a person is diabetic. Achieved accuracies of 77.6% and found 5 out of 8 features statistically significant.
- R-Tree (July 2012 Dec 2012) Programmed a Graphical User Interface (Java frontend) for spatial information querying to visualize algorithms in "R-Trees A Dynamic Index Structure for Spatial Searching" by Guttman [1984] used in databases for indexing multi-dimensional information.

## **Awards and Recognitions**

- Won Cerner Masters, Cerner's highest engineering award among all global associates in Feb 2016.
- Awarded Chancellors Merit Scholarship offered to the top 3% of the cohort.

#### **Research Publications**

Amol Parikh, Nidhi Sharma and Jeris J Alan. Article: Modified Fast Bandwidth-Constrained Shortest
 Path Algorithm for MACO. International Journal of Computer Applications 69(23):41-44, May 2013